(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T22:50:32.303271",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Whew~ Another hard day's work done...
Huh? Morning already?
And the weather's actually perfect!
Wow!
I'm so exhausted...
And starving.
Honestly, someone should be making me breakfast right now.
Surely there's someone out there willing to take care of me.
Maybe a little walk will help me recharge.
Then I'll invite someone over.
I don't know. Who's around at this hour?
I gotta think about this.
Oww...
Where am I?
Last thing I remember, I got hit by a car...
Whoa, that's a pretty fancy throne.
Does someone important live here or something?
Ah! So you're the one who ran me over earlier!
Why were you even driving a car?!
Wait...
You can drive?!
With those tiny little arms and legs?
There's no way you could even reach the pedals!
That's why you messed up and ran me over, isn't it?!
You know where we are?
How do you not know?!
It's because of you that I'm stuck in some place I don't even recognize!!
Finally found you!
Kronii, Warden of Time!
What a long journey it's been... Took forever.
You're not about to tell me you don't even know how to get back home... right?
They're really going at it.
Maybe we should join in too!
If you're saying we should sneak in and attack... sure, but... I don't want to join.
But we can take them down while they're distracted by fighting!
Gigi! CC!
So, one of the Kronies ran me over with a car, and when I came to, I was here!
When I came to, I was here!
Do you know where this place is?
Why does she know who we are?
And what's a "Kronie," anyway?
She doesn't seem to know where she is, but...
...isn't she supposed to be the boss here?
Yeah.
And she kinda looks weak...
What's going on...? What?
Let's beat her and become heroes!
Huh?!
Argh! Die, scum! Die! Now!
die,
you filthy, filthy, filthy...
Okay, that's a little too far. Hey...
Okay, you need to chill out. What?
Kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
Don't kill me!
What? Wait, w-why are you even attacking me?
I mean, you're the boss here, right?
We came here to become heroes!
Huh? Ah, so we're playing hero and villain. Okay.
Okay, I get you.
Playing?
It's... It's real!
Okay. Yeah, sure.
Then if I win,
I want you two to cook for me and then take care of me, meow~!
Uh-ew...
I don't... no thank you.
Don't worry, kitten. I'll take care of you.
Ha ha ha!
Okay.
I don't want to be your pet.
Oh!
Ha ha ha!
Oh?
Loser.
One?!
Ha ha ha!
There was one damage.
Even for pretend play.
Okay.
Why are your attacks stronger than mine?
Wow, you're pretty weak for a boss, aren't you?
And, no, she does the right amount of damage for a kitten.
Ha ha ha!
Die!
Oh, okay, you can stop.
Okay, um am I really the boss?
Why are you two my enemies? I just want to go home.
ddyaahhuuuu uaaaa...
Something suddenly feels really bad!
Stand behind me. It's okay, I'll tank it.
The? What? What is this?
Magic is suddenly... coming out on its own!
Okay, don't! Why did you take it that way?
No, BAD! Argh!
No! Oh! Aah!
I actually beat them.
Oh!
Oh. What was that just now?
Am I... am I just really goated?
I'm really strong.
But why did it happen on its own?
I won, but now there's nobody left to pamper me.
Unhappy?
If you're dealing with a lotta woes
Unlucky?
Then you got to listen very close
Be happy!
Keep on trying, never give up
Don't forget that you're alive
The past you have been running from
That boring future yet to come
Still counseling you
Oh my, oh my
Universal
Peace, peace yeah
Unhappy?
Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead, oh
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Somehow feeling like there's a fight within
And it's been going on so long
I don't feel it and don't even wanna try
Past version of me, of me, of me, of me
And those figures of the old
Transparent ghosts over my route
The childish and painful memories have the deepest roots
Saddening?
Nowhere to be seen
Say what?
Way better then? Irony
They all see the me of the past when looking at me now
Nonsense
Label I can't erase
Yes!
In essence, a complex
It's almost like something's possessing me
It is wrapping tight around
And won't loosen its bounds
The self I used to be before
Undead, oh
Still alive
Time is a chain of your own path
To be alive is to always embrace your inner changes
On and on
Don't settle for unhappiness
Don't be complacent in distress
Not even trying to seize the joy and be happy, you coward
Oh, this world, oh, this world is one odd, one odd fantasy
Who knows what is coming up next, a monster or a snake?
This is a story starting after that encounter, finally
With people or monsters and spirits
feeling inside
There's nothing left to view
Lived long enough, nothing is new
No sign of anything wonderful waiting down the line
Saddening
Too much knowledge results in feeling like every myth is but another boring evolution
Thrill is what I really want now
Bored and down, used to frowns
And this is the way the guidance grew
Rising compliance too
It's like I'm going under a lid
I consumed everything
This one or that one or, whichever and now it all just tastes the same
Undead, oh
Still alive, time is a chain of your own path
In any era, your past and your future are in this very moment
Fulfill the life you're set upon
And truthfully keep moving on
Go for that happy ending
Undead, oh
Still alive, I'm telling this to you now
So never give up on pursuing your happiness and keep being human
'Cause being numb to suffering, always enduring everything
It's almost as if you're dead, a lot of corpses undead, oh
If you're dealing with a lotta woes
Then you gotta listen very close
Keep on trying, never give up
Be aware that you're alive
Drowning deep in unhappiness
Or seizing that true happiness
It's on you, on you, it's all on you
Universal, all-embracing
All creations, peace, peace, yeah
Past and future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
Where people gather and go
You'll find all worries and woes
Oh, you gotta live on through this tale of
Monsters everywhere that you can see
あなた
You
わたし
Me
ふたり
The two of us
ぼっち
Alone
みらい
The future
くらい
So dark
どこへ
Where shall we...
いこうか
...go?
悲しみが壊れて死にそうだ
Sadness breaks down, I feel like I'm going to die
星空に泣き声が響くのさ
Cries echo into the starry sky
ああああ
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
ひろい
The vast...
せかい
...world
なにを
What shall we...
うたおうか
...sing?
悲しみがあふれて泣きそうだ
Sadness overflows, I feel like crying
握りしめたその手が冷たくて
The hand I held tightly was so cold
ああああ
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
悲しみが壊れて死にそうだ
Sadness breaks down, I feel like I'm going to die
星空に泣き声が響くのさ
Cries echo into the starry sky
悲しみがあふれて泣きそうだ
Sadness overflows, I feel like crying
君の声が彼方に消えていく
Your voice fades away into the distance
ああああ
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
I turned both of them into undead...
Eyyy!
I thought I'd finally been reunited with my friends, too.
And now I'm all alone in this gloomy place.
Hm? What's this?
My name... HP...
Is this one of those typical status screens?
Oh, I've seen these. I've seen these.
Wait, I love this.
Okay, Let's see. What's it say?
Okay, Kronii.
Like sleep. Yeah. Okay. That makes sense.
Oh pet play...?
Oh what?
Since when did I become a pet?
I'm not even into those.
I should be the owner.
Not that I'm into that to begin with,
but, that's scary.
It's like someone's weird fantasy got mixed in here.
That's not mine.
Oh, okay.
Oh, there's even a keyword for recording the story.
Everyone watching this,
make sure to use that keyword when you document it
and share it with other people, okay?
Well. And, Oh, yeah. Another thing.
That magic from earlier?
I know you guys are the ones giving the commands.
What kind of person would make me cast something like that at my friends?!
But it was really powerful, wasn't it?
Oh, it completely caught me off guard.
Oh. With magic like that, I can beat anybody.
And even if I could, I wouldn't wanna use it on my friends.
That would suck.
Oh. I wonder how I'm supposed to get back home.
I just want to eat someone's cooking already!
Oh, And I've been trying my best, so I want everyone to praise me, too.
Meow!
I'm crashing out.
Oh. If I'm the boss of this place, that means-
that means I can sit in that throne, right?
Oh, that's so cool.
Wait. I'm so excited.
Okay. Well, for now, I'm just going to sit in the chair and take a break.
Yeah. Okay.
まてよ そこゆく娘さん 逆子宿らせ
Hold on a sec, young lady with a breech baby in your belly,
あどけの足らない そんな身体に
and that body with so little innocence left.
ただしく回らん 愚図の頭で
With that foolish, useless head of yours that won't turn properly,
天真爛漫!? ほざくな 馬鹿め。
are you acting all naive and pure? Get a grip, you fool.
まちな そこゆく兄さん 何の片割れ？
Hold on a sec, young man. What kind of scum are you?
ちいさなあの娘の 御花を咲かせ、
Plucking that little girl's precious flower,
指きりげんまん 星の彼方へ
and promising her the moon before taking to your heels?
陽関三畳！？ くたばれ 雑魚め。
Leaving her with a few parting words?! Go to hell, you weakling.
「いついつ出やるの？ かごめよかごめ」
"When, oh when is it coming out? Pregnant girl, oh pregnant girl."
嫌味をからげて 嘲うあなたへ
To you who sneer with malicious sarcasm,
ぴたりと重ねて 吐き出す情け
I spew out this pity born from intimate nights.
誰しもがやがては 地獄の奥底へ 連れて行かれる
In the end, everyone will be dragged down to the depths of hell.
あー、触れあって 埋めあって 勝ち取った 幸せを
Ah, after touching and comforting each other, the happiness won...
盗まれた正義のヒーローが泣いている。
The hero of justice whose happiness was stolen is crying.
抱きあって 叩きあって 分ちあった あの頃を、
Those days when we held each other, fought, and shared together...
忘れてしまえたら どれほど楽だろうか。
How much easier it would be if I could just forget them completely.
擦り切れ た肌 かさぶた いかれた 山場
Chaffed skin and scabs, wild high points.
愛しさ交えて 痛む片腹
Mixed with affection, laughing till my sides ache.
またまたわがままばかりのかなまさか？
Don't tell me you're acting selfish all over again?
まだまだきつそうだな
Still looking pretty tough...
そろそろみんなに？「追いつかないと！」
About time to... "Catch up to everyone!"
うわごと混じりに？「衝撃回路！」
Mixing in delirium... "Shock circuit!"
視界を滲ませ？「はかどる迷子！」
Blurring vision... "Making progress as a lost child!"
誰もが元から 未来の材料へ
Everyone was originally meant to be material for the future...
あてられている
Assigned to it.
あー、着飾って 痛がってもぎとった幸せを
Ah, dressing up, acting in pain, the happiness plucked away...
盗まれた悲劇のヒロインが泣いている
The stolen tragic heroine is crying.
わけあって かけあって 重ねあった思い出を
All those reasons, interactions, shared memories...
忘れてしまえたらどれほど楽だろうか
How much easier would it be if I could just forget them all?
強がったって 嘘はばれるぞ
Acting tough, the lies will be exposed.
怖がったって 血は流れるぞ
Acting scared, blood will still flow.
匿った 傷口開くぞ
Hidden wounds will open up.
「嫌がったって 傷は痛むぞ」
"Even if you hate it, the wound will hurt."
じゃれあって 眺めあって 語りあったあのときを
Playfully teasing, gazing, talking to each other back then...
思い回しては悲観に暮れてみる
Ruminating on it, sinking into pessimism.
駆け寄って 寄り添って 笑いあったあのときを
Running up, leaning close, laughing together back then...
いっそきれいに 忘れてしまいたいんだ
I'd rather just cleanly forget it all.
Welcome to the mind fuck
Welcome to the mind fuck, mind fuck
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
Okay たちまち独壇場 Listen listen
Okay, instantly a one-person show, listen, listen
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
振り切ろう
Let's shake it off
ヤーヤーヤーヤーヤー 唱タイム
Yah-yah-yah-yah-yah, show time
天辺の御成り ほらおいで
Behold the summit's grand arrival, come on over
宵をコンプリート オーライ Hell yeah, yeah, yeah
Complete the night, alright, hell yeah, yeah, yeah
だんだんノリノリで超簡単 Brah, brah, brah, pow
Getting more and more into the rhythm, super easy, brah, brah, brah, pow
えも言われ無い Ain't nobody stop (ha, ha)
Beyond words, ain't nobody stop (ha, ha)
全土絢爛豪華 Attention 騒ごうか
The realm shines in stunning splendor, attention, shall we make some noise?
意思表示にもうじき衝撃の声高らか 堂々登板
Soon comes an impressive debut, expressing purpose with a loud voice
もう伽藍洞は疾っくの疾う 淘汰
The empty void has long since been eliminated
Ay 繚乱桜花 御出座しだ Ah
Ay, cherry blossoms bloom madly, behold the grand arrival, ah
格好つけてるつもりは No, no
I don't mean to show off, no, no
オートマティックに溢れちゃう本能
It's automatic, natural instincts overflow
宣う断頭台の上で躁げ華麗
On top of the proclaiming gallows, go wild gracefully
Da-rat-a-tat-a, warning!
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
万歳 遊ぶ気に寿 Shout it out, shout it out
Hooray, rejoice in the spirit of delight, shout it out, shout it out
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
はんなり感情通りに八艘飛び Shout it out, shout it out
Elegantly soaring, let emotions guide, shout it out, shout it out
食らっちゃいな
Eat it up
Rat-tat-tat-tat-tat (pull up)
満開総員一気にとびきり Jump around
Full bloom, all at once with full force, jump around
Look at me now 皮膚を破りそうな程に跳ねる心臓
Look at me now, heart pounding so hard it could tear through skin
くらい激情
Immensely passionate
Exotic vox
イニミニマニモ
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe
ご来場からのご来光
A grand sunrise following your arrival
かくれんぼしてるその気持ち解放
Release those feelings playing hide-and-seek
しゃかりきじみちゃう
Becoming recklessly intense
蛇腹刃蛇尾 騙る二枚刃
Serpent blade, serpent tail, a deceitful double-edged sword
野心家 嫉妬するようなジュース
Ambitionists, a juice to make one jealous
たぶらかすな かっとなっちゃ嫌
Don't deceive, don't lose your temper
カルマに至る前に揺蕩うわ
Swaying before reaching karma
十色のバタフライ
Ten-colored butterfly
No escape
ご存じの通り 騒々しい鼓動に
As you know, bound by this noisy heartbeat
絆されて もう止まれない
Bound tight, I can't stop anymore
衝動に塗装し 描いた Daybreak
Painting daybreak with impulsive hues
肺貫通低音狂
Maddening bass tones piercing through the lungs
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
異例の危険度 比類なき活気充満
Unprecedented danger level, filled with peerless vitality
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
いちかばちか鳴呼
All or nothing, ah
Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah-Nah, Ready for my show
引き起こすために Stay
To make it happen, stay
一切合切忘れて Shout it out!
Forget everything and shout it out!
右に左にまとめて Rat-ta-ta-ta
To the right, to the left, together, rat-ta-ta-ta!
思いっきり Clap your hands!
Clap your hands with all your might!
何はともあれ Shout it out! Shout it out!
Anyway, shout it out! Shout it out!
駄目 駄目 駄目 脳みその中から 「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
"No, no, no," morality screams from inside my brain, "Stop it, idiot!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン 半端なくラブ！ときらめき浮き足立つフィロソフィ
Darling, baby darling, an extreme "I love you!" A sparkling, restless philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
Deadly cute, an upward glance,
なにかしら法に触れるくらい
It'd probably break some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Spreading madness everywhere, before I know it, I've spent myself dry.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
It's your fault for being born into this world.
やたらとしんどい 恋煩い
This lovesickness is ridiculously painful,
バラバランなる頭とこの身体
My head and body are falling apart.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て
When "I love you" gushes out from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう あばらの奥を
What on earth am I supposed to do with these feelings deep inside my ribs?
ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The coarse sugar melts, making me feel like throwing up.
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にしそう
My pupils open wide, like I'm about to drown to death.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this whole world, only you are the correct answer!
Darlin Baby Darlin
Darling, baby darling...
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない 君だけルールは適用外
Even if everything flipped upside down, there's no way I could win; you alone are exempt from the rules.
四つともオセロは黒しかない カツアゲ放題
All four Othello pieces are black, you can rob me blind.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
The Avada Kedavra you cast with a smile leaves a stigma on my forehead, sorry about that!
矢を刺して 貫いて ここ弱点
Shoot the arrow, pierce right through me, this is my weak spot!
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
Deadly cute, an upward glance,
なにかしら法に触れるくらい
It'd probably break some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Spreading madness everywhere, before I know it, I've spent myself dry.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
It's your fault for being born into this world.
パチモンでもいい 何でもいい
A knockoff is fine, anything is fine,
今君と名付いてる全て欲しい
I want everything that bears your name right now.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て
When "I love you" gushes out from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
一体どうしよう
What on earth am I supposed to do?
この想いをどうしよう あばらの奥を
What do I do with these feelings deep inside my ribs?
ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The coarse sugar melts, making me feel like throwing up.
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にしそう
My pupils open wide, like I'm about to drown to death.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this whole world, only you are the correct answer!
Darlin Baby Darlin
Darling, baby darling...
カエラ！
Kaela!
クロニー！やっと知ってる人に会えた！
Kronii! Finally, someone I know!
私もだよ〜！
Yeah, me too!
ここどこなの？
Where even are we?
帰りたいのに帰れないの
I wanna go home, but I can't...
私も帰れなくて困ってたんだけど
Well, I've been stuck here too, and couldn't find a way back.
もう帰れないなら 楽しむしかないと思うんだよね
But if we can't leave, I figured we might as well enjoy ourselves.
すごく前向きだけど
You know, that's a pretty positive attitude, but...
ここから帰りたくないの？
Don't you wanna go home?
帰りたいよ？
Of course I do.
そういえば
Well, you know, come to think of it,
君はここで何をしてるの？クロニー？
What are you doing here, Kronii?
なんかここのボスらしくて ここから出られないの
So apparently, I'm some kind of boss here, and I can't leave this place.
...甘やかしてくれる人もいないし
...And there's nobody around to spoil on me either.
おや、甘やかしてほしいの？
Oh, you want someone to spoil you?
なら私がよしよししてあげるよ
I can give you some head pats if you like.
へぇ...ほんと？あなたはそれでいいの？
Heh... really? You're okay with that?
もちろん！おいで！おいで！
Yeah, sure! Come here! Come here!
にゃ〜！
Meow!
私もボスだったけど誰も来なくて
I was a boss too, but nobody ever came to see me.
寂しいからこの世界から出たかったんだ
I got lonely, so I wanted to leave this world.
寂しかったからここを離れたかったの？
You wanted to leave because you were lonely?
わ 私ね ジジとセシリアと戦うことになって
I, I ended up fighting Gigi and CC,
何が起きてるのかさっぱり分からなかったのに
and I had no idea what was going on.
まぁ 私のところには人が来なくて探検に来たんだ
Well, nobody came to my place, so I decided to go exploring.
そうだ！私とも戦ってくれる？楽しそう！
Alright! Will you fight me too? It sounds fun!
ちゃんと聞いてないよね...
You aren't really listening, are you...
戦いだって楽しんだもん勝ちだよ！いくよ！
A battle is only fun if you enjoy it! Here I come!
いったいどうしちゃったの？
What's wrong with you?
私の武器はハンマー！
So my weapon is a hammer.
いくよ！
Here I come!
やぁー！
Hya!
適当にあしらって終わらせようかな
Maybe I'll just humor her and get this over with.
本気でやらないとおもしろくないよ！
It's no fun if you don't take it seriously!
本気出したらやっつけちゃうでしょ！！
But if I do, I'll end up defeating you!!
大丈夫 大丈夫！ほら来い！
It's fine, it's fine. Come on, hit me with it.
Well, don't say I didn't warn you.
Ohoooo!
Yeah. See, I told you.
That was awesome!
Huh?
That was amazing!
Oh, you're the amazing one!
Well, that was fun.
So let's stop worrying about this world,
sing, dance,
and have a good time before we head home!
I'm fine with the singing and dancing part,
but isn't this a little sudden?
And how exactly are you planning on getting us home?
Well...
I don't know!
純情？何それ 愛情？何それ
Pure heart? What's that? Romance? What's that?
美味しいの？ねぇ 美味しいの？ってば
Is it yummy? Hey, is it yummy, I said!
乱暴ダメダメ 感情捨て去り いっせーので ぶっ飛ばすだけ
Violence is a big no-no, throw away feelings, on three, just blow it all away!
混沌ブギウギ ハッピー特盛り ドンピシャイだ ドンピシャイだもん
Chaos boogie-woogie, extra large serving of happy! Right on target, because it's right on target!
だんだん落ちてく IQくそわる いっせーので 死ぬまで踊れ
My IQ is dropping fast, it's so bad! On three, dance until you die!
完全体の山田
Yamada in perfect form,
無関心なんてありえない
it's impossible to be indifferent to it.
3000体の桑田の方がいいかな
Maybe 3,000 Kuwatas would be better...
わがままばかりじゃ落ち着かない
Being selfish all the time won't calm me down,
冷や汗が出すぎて気持ち悪い
breaking out in a cold sweat makes me feel sick.
当たり前のことも手につかない
I can't even focus on everyday things,
もう何て言ったらいい？ばかりで
saying 'What should I even say?' over and over.
世間体とか投げ出したい
I want to throw away social appearances,
狂ったように泣き出したい
I want to burst into tears like crazy,
思うがまま生きて消えていきたいな
I want to live as I please and just fade away.
純情？何それ 愛情？何それ
Pure heart? What's that? Romance? What's that?
美味しいの？ねぇ 美味しいの？ってば
Is it yummy? Hey, is it yummy, I said!
乱暴ダメダメ 感情捨て去り いっせーので ぶっ飛ばすだけ
Violence is a big no-no, throw away feelings, on three, just blow it all away!
混沌ブギウギ ハッピー特盛り ドンピシャイだ ドンピシャイだもん
Chaos boogie-woogie, extra large serving of happy! Right on target, because it's right on target!
だんだん落ちてく IQくそわる いっせーので 死ぬまで踊れ
My IQ is dropping fast, it's so bad! On three, dance until you die!
ワンツー 禍々 三四 刈り取り もういいんだって もういいんだって もう
One, two, calamity! Three, four, harvest! It's enough already, it's enough already, enough!
ハッピーおかわり ギブミーときめき いっせーので さあ飛び込め
Second helping of happy, give me excitement! On three, come on, jump right in!
本能ブギウギ 混沌特盛り もういいんだって もういいんだって もう
Instinct boogie-woogie, extra serving of chaos! It's enough already, it's enough already, enough!
最低ヤツらの ライカミステリー いっせーので ぶっ飛ばすだけ
Like a mystery of the worst scum! On three, just blow it all away!
混沌ブギウギ ハッピー特盛り ドンピシャイだ ドンピシャイだもん
Chaos boogie-woogie, extra large serving of happy! Right on target, because it's right on target!
だんだん落ちてく 人生くそわる いっせーので 死ぬまで踊れ
My life quality is dropping fast, it's so bad! On three, dance until you die!
もういいや 全部全部ほら 忘れてしまおう
Forget it all, look, let's just forget everything!
簡単なことじゃないが 我々ならできるだろう
It's not an easy thing, but we can do it, right?
なぁ？ Get down
Right? Get down!
頭でわかっては嘆いた
I understood in my head and lamented,
転がっていく様子を嗤った
sneered at the way things tumbled down.
寂しいとか愛とかわかんない
I don't understand loneliness or love,
人間の形は投げ出したんだ
I've abandoned my human form.
抱えきれない 言葉だらけの存在証明を
An overwhelming proof of existence filled with words...
この小さな劇場から出られらんない
I can't escape from this small theater,
気づいたら最後逃げ出したい
once I realize it, I just want to run away.
僕ら全員演じていたんだ
Every single one of us was acting,
エンドロールに向かってゆくんだ
heading straight towards the end credits.
さあ皆必死に役を演じて 傍観者なんていないのさ
Come on, everyone desperately play your role, there are no bystanders here.
“ワタシ”なんてないの
There is no 'Me',
どこにだって居ないよ
I'm nowhere to be found.
ずっと僕は 何者にもなれないで
All along, I've been unable to become anyone...
僕ら今 さあさあ 喰らいあって
Now then, come on, let's devour each other,
延長戦 サレンダーして メーデー
surrender in overtime, Mayday!
淡い愛想 垂れ流し 言の愛憎
Spilling faint compliments, love and hate in words.
ドラマチックな展開を どっか期待してんだろ
Deep down, you're expecting a dramatic plot twist, aren't you?
君も YES YES 息を呑んで
You too, YES YES, hold your breath,
采配は そこにあんだ ヘッドショット
the direction is right there, headshot!
騒ぐ想いも その心撃ち抜いて
Shoot through your restless thoughts and that heart of yours.
さあ まだ見ぬ糸を引いて
Come on, pull the unseen strings,
黒幕のお出ましさ
it's time for the mastermind to make an entrance.
その目に映るのは
What is reflected in those eyes...
触れたら壊れてしまった
Touched and it broke completely,
間違っていく様子を黙った
I kept silent as things went wrong.
僕ら全員無垢でありました
We were all innocent back then,
いつのまにやら怪物になったんだ
but before we knew it, we became monsters.
その全てを肯定しないと前に進めないかい
Must we accept all of it to move forward?
『まあ君にはきっと無理なんだ』
"Well, it's probably impossible for you."
「だから君にはきっと無理なんだ」
"That's why it's surely impossible for you."
いつのまにやら外野にいたんだ
Before I knew it, I was on the sidelines,
そんなガヤばっかり飛ばしてきたんだ
spewing nothing but useless noise.
皆必死に自分を守って 救いの手を待ってるのさ
Everyone desperately protects themselves, waiting for a helping hand.
考えたくはないよ 馬鹿になっていたんだもん
I don't wanna think about it, I just wanted to stay foolish.
ずっと僕は 何者にもなれないで
All along, unable to become anyone...
だから今 前線上
So now, on the front lines,
その旗は高く舞って
that flag flies high.
劣勢 頼る相棒 言葉すら必要ないよ
At a disadvantage, a trusted partner, no words needed.
ドラマチックな展開はドットヒットしていくだろう
The dramatic turn of events will surely build up.
君も YES YES 息を呑んで 再会を誓いあって
You too, yes yes, holding your breath, promising to meet again.
ワンチャンスしかない僕の一瞬を賭けるのさ
Betting my one brief moment with only one chance.
クライマックスみたいな 手に汗を握るのさ
A gripping, climax-like feeling.
ぽつりと呟いた
Muttered quietly,
隠してきた真実はどこにもない
the truth I've hidden is nowhere to be found.
嗤ってきた奴らに居場所はない
There's no place for those who sneered.
思い出してぽいってして感情はない
Remembering then tossing it aside, no emotions left.
流した涙 理由なんてない
No reason for the tears shed.
優しさに温度も感じられない
Can't even feel the warmth in kindness.
差し伸べた手に疑いしかない
Only doubt towards extended hands.
穴が空いて愛は垂れてしまいになったんだ
A hole opened up, and love leaked out completely.
倒れそうな僕を覗き込んだんだ
Looking down at me as I was about to collapse.
諦めかけた人の前にアンタはいつも嗤うようにおでましさ
Before those about to give up, you always appear with a sneer.
君にはどんな風に見えてるんだい
How does it look to you?
呼吸を整えてさ
Catching my breath...
さあ
Now,
ずっと僕は 何者にもなれないで
all along, unable to become anyone...
僕ら今さあさあ 喰らいあって 延長戦 サレンダーして メーデー 淡い愛想 垂れ流し 言の愛憎
Now we devour each other, extra time, surrendering, Mayday, spilling faint affection and hatred of words.
ドラマチックな展開をどっか期待してんだろ
Expecting a dramatic development somewhere.
君も YES YES 息を呑んで 采配はそこにあんだ
You too, yes yes, holding your breath, control is right there.
ヘッドショット 騒ぐ想いも その心撃ち抜いて さあ
Headshot, shooting through those raging feelings and that heart, come on.
まだ見ぬ糸を引いて 黒幕のお出ましさ
Pulling unseen strings, the mastermind appears.
その目に映るのは
Reflected in those eyes is...
セレナーデ
[Title: Serenade]
都合のいい思いを燃やして 呆れた願いはもう手放した
Burning convenient memories, I've let go of my absurd wishes.
裏切りや秘密が漂って ここから動けない
Betrayals and secrets drift about, I can't move from here.
生まれてしまった あるいは壊れてしまった あの日のあの場所でずっと 止まったままでいた未来
Born into this, or perhaps broken, at that time and place, a future stopped in its tracks.
それでも 心のどこかで君を感じていた 許せない 今の僕は誰？
Even so, somewhere in my heart I felt you, unable to forgive, who am I now?
ねぇ ずっとずっとそばにいたんだ 「勘違いだ」って 嘘じゃないよ
Hey, I was by your side all along, "a misunderstanding", it's not a lie.
望んだものじゃなくとも あなたに出会えた痛みだけが 愛だって信じられるように
Even if it wasn't what I wished for, so that I can believe the pain of meeting you is love.
僕に触れないで！ 祈る セレナーデ 僕なしで上手く幸せになってね
Don't touch me! Praying serenade, please be happy without me.
誰よりもずっと 何を手放しても これが愛だって信じていた 罰をください
More than anyone, whatever I let go of, I believed this was love, please punish me.
誰でもない あなた あなただけ 世界がまだ忘れてくれなくても
No one else, only you, even if the world hasn't forgotten yet.
きっと まだ あなた あなただけ 願い疲れても歌うよ セレナーデ
Surely, still only you, even if tired of wishing, I'll sing a serenade.
願い疲れても歌うよ セレナーデ
Even if tired of wishing, I'll sing a serenade.
シナリオ通りのコメディ 不幸自慢はハーモニー？ エゴイスティックに光った瞳の中に映っている「あなた」は「誰？」
A comedy according to scenario, bragging about misfortune in harmony? In those egoistically shining eyes, who is the "you" reflected?
暗闇が光らせた舞台の上で 何も知らずにただ踊っていられたならよかった
On a stage illuminated by darkness, if only I could dance knowing nothing.
希望も不幸も身勝手だ 僕らは 全員共犯者だった
Hope and misfortune are selfish, we were all accomplices.
疑う余地もないほど 運命が定まった あの夜から 僕らは愛し方を忘れた
Leaving no room for doubt, fate was set, from that night, we forgot how to love.
これだけ願って これだけ祈って こんな 悲しい結末でごめんね
Wishing this much, praying this much, I'm sorry for such a sad ending.
すべて失って すべて消え去っても ただ 君がずっと生きていた 痛みが欲しい
Even if losing everything and everything fades away, I just want the pain of you living on.
あと何回数えたら あと何回傷つけば あと何回失えば あと何回壊れたら
How many more times counting, how many more times hurt, how many more times losing, how many more times broken...
あと何回数えたら あと何回傷つけば
How many more times counting, how many more times hurt...
あと何回数えたら
How many more times must I count?
あと何回傷つけば
How many more times must I be hurt?
あと何回許せば
How many more times must I forgive?
あと何回失えば
How many more times must I lose?
この想いは満たされる？
Before these feelings are fulfilled?
これだけ願って
Wishing this much,
これだけ祈って
praying this much,
こんな悲しい結末でごめんなさい
I'm sorry for such a sad conclusion.
全て失って
Even if I lose everything,
全て違っても
even if everything changes,
ただ僕がずっと愛していた君よ
to you, whom I have always loved:
消えないで 祈るセレナーデ
Please don't fade away... A serenade of prayer.
泣かないで 幸せになってね
Please don't cry... Be happy, okay?
誰よりもずっと
More than anyone else, forever...
何を手放しても
No matter what I let go of,
これが愛だって信じてた
I believed that this was love.
罰をくだせ
Hand down my punishment.
誰もいない あなた あなただけ
There's no one else... You, only you.
世界がまだ 忘れてくれなくても
Even if the world still hasn't forgotten...
きっとまだ あなた あなただけ
Surely still, you, only you,
願い疲れても 歌うよ セレナーデ
even if tired of wishing, I will sing a serenade.
雨が降り注いでも
Even if the rain pours down,
僕じゃなくても
even if it isn't me,
願い疲れても 歌うよ セレナーデ
even if tired of wishing, I will sing a serenade.
クロニー！
Kronii!
助けに来たよ！
I've come to save you!
やっぱりスバル先輩！
I knew it, Subaru-senpai!
どうして助けが必要ってわかったんですか？
How'd'ya know I needed help?
ずっと見てたからね！
I've been watching the whole time!
ずっと見てたんですか...？
The whole time...?
私も？
And me?
見てたよ
I watch you.
あぁ そうですか
Oh, okay.
それは怖いですけど
That's scary, but
なんで？！
The Why?!
だったらもっと早く助けてほしかったです！
I, I wish you helped me a lot sooner then!
途中から楽しそうにしてたから
Well, you started having fun halfway through,
どうなるか見守ろうかなと思って！
so I figured I'd see how things played out!
うん
Yeah
見てた...
I watched...
ただ
just the
世界を
world.
オッケー うん
Okay. Yeah.
あぁ 世界ね わかりました！
Oh, yeah. The world. Yeah.
まあ確かに楽しかった部分もあったかも
Yeah. I mean, I guess I did end up enjoying parts of it.
でしょ？！
See?!
だから 本当に助けが必要なのかなって思ってたんだよ！
That's why I was wondering whether you actually needed saving!
あぁ 一応ありがとうございます
Aw... well thank you, I guess,
でも本当に ここから出るのを手伝ってくれるんですか？
but can you really help me get out of here?
あと...
Just...
待って
Please wait.
どこ見てるんですか？
where are you looking?
あと1曲だけ
Just one more song.
心を込めて歌って踊れば
If you sing and dance your heart out,
家に帰れるよ！
you can go home!
本当に？ やった！
Really? Yay!
世界を見てみて！
Just watch the world!
世界！
The world!
あぁ あれが世界なんだ
Oh, so that's the world.
オッケー 待ってごめん 見入っちゃってた
Oh, okay. Wait. Sorry. I was so fascinated.
スタッフさん
Please staff
下上下上下上下上
Down up up up up up up.
そうそう！
Yeah, yeah!
本当に？！
Really?!
カエラも戦って歌ったあとに消えたでしょう？
Kaela disappeared after fighting and singing, right?
あれは元の世界に帰ったからなんだよ！
That's because she went back to the original world.
戦って歌ったあとに？
After fighting and singing?
待って それって私も戦わなきゃいけないってことですか？
Wait, does that mean I have to fight too?
うん！
Yep!
そう...
Oh...
わけわかんない！
I don't get it!
なんでそもそも戦わなきゃいけないの？！
Why do we have to fight at all?!
何かの儀式みたいなものだと思って！
Think of it like some kind of ritual!
オッケー じゃあそこに立って攻撃を受けるだけね
Okay, then we just stand there and take the hit,
それで現実世界に戻ったら
and when we get back to the real world,
ご飯を作って 私のこと甘やかしてもらうから！！！
you're going to make me food and spoil me!!!
やめろ！ お願いやめて！ やめて！
Stop! Please stop please stop please.
ちょっと！
YOU!
正気か？！
Are you okay?!
正気なの？！
ちょっと待って なんでスバルがご飯作るの？！
Wait, why should I cook for you?!
それに さっきもう甘やかしてもらってたでしょ！
And besides, you were already getting spoiled earlier!
とにかく！
Anyway!
楽しむのが大事！
You should have fun!
喜びこそが鍵なんだよ！！
Joy is the key!!
ほんとかなあ？
You sure about that?
じゃあ楽しませてください
Then you have to entertain me.
にゃ〜！
Meow!
にゃ〜？
Meow?
大丈夫...？
Are you okay...?
とにかく！
Anyway!
スバ友召喚！
I summon Subatomo!
スバ友マジで可愛い！
Subatomo is soooo cute!
マジで可愛いでしょ？ ね？
This is "super cute" right?
うん でも
Yeah, but
すごくちっちゃい
so tiny.
ちっちゃい？
Tiny?
すごく小さい
It's so small.
うん！
Yeah!
小さいのが可愛い！
Small is cute!
見るだけで幸せになるでしょ？
Just looking at it makes you happy, right?
Yeah. I mean, it's...
...very adorable, but,
...I'm...
...I'm also right here too.
Meow~
meow meow~
クロニーもマジで可愛い！
Kronii is super cute, too!
でも　でも
But, but this is...
これなに？
What is this?
シャイクロニー？
Shy Kronii?
No!
違います～　やめてくださいよ～！
No, stoppppppp!
クロニーは　にゃーなの？
Is Kronii a cat?
私　私は...それでいいです
I-I-it's fine.
わからないなら　もういいです
If you don't know, then, never mind.
うん　もうなんでもいいや
It's... it's whatever
ちょっと　怖すぎるよクロニー！
That's... way too creepy, Kronii!
ねぇ！なんで?!
HEY, what's that mean?!
今日のクロニーはちょっと　ちょっと大丈夫かな？
Today Kronii is a little, little are you okay?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
私は大丈夫じゃないけど　そんなこと言わないで！
Hey, that's.. I'm never okay, But you shouldn't say that!
というか　戦うんですよね？
Anyway, aren't we supposed to fight though?
うん　よし！
Yeah. All right!
スバ友大丈夫？
Subatomo, are you okay?
いけ！スバ友！
Go Subatomo!
よし　攻撃！行け　行け　行け　行け！
Yeah! Attack! Go go go go!
攻撃！攻撃！
Attack! Attack!
おまえー！！
You!!
来い！
Come!
戻れ　戻れ　戻れ　戻れ！！
Back back back back!!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
なんか...
Subatomo...
ちょっと弱いかもー
might be a little underwhelming...
ウィークかもこいつ
This lil guy's a weakling
さぁ　そろそろ準備しようかな
Well, I guess I should start getting prepared.
全然痛くない
It doesn't even hurt.
くすぐったくもない　ごめんね～
Not even tickle. Sorry.
やばいぞ！やばい！
This is bad! Really bad!
スバ友！
Subatomo!!
一緒に受けよう！
We're taking this one together!
やばい！やばい！
Oh no! Oh no!
もう身代わりだよお前が！
We're taking this one together!
助けて　お願いだよ　お願い！
Please, mercy! Please, mercy! Please!
いくよー
Here I go...
わあああ！
Waaah!
そんなのなってないよ...
That's terrible...
イェー！
Yayyy.
ごめんね　でも　イェー！！
I'm sorry, but yayyyyy.
スバ友ーーー！
Subatomo----!
大丈夫かスバ友！
Are you okay, Subatomo!
おお　生きてる　よかった
Oh it's alive, oh thank god, okay.
大変だった
That was rough.
ほら　楽しんでるでしょ！
See? You're having fun!
たぶんこれで家に帰れるはず！
This should probably get you home now!
頑張って！
Good luck!
イェー！ありがとう！
Yeah! Thank you!
バイ！
Bye.
帰ろう！
Go home!
なんだったんだろう...
What was that...
何が起きているのかよくわからないけど
I don't really get what's going on, but
どうやら最後にもう１曲歌えば家に帰れるみたい
apparently I can go home if I sing one last song.
じゃあ　やってみよう
So let's do that.
待って　これなに？
Wait. What's this?
なに？　うん　うん
What? Okay, okay.
上から順番に１つずつ見てみようか
Let's go through them one by one from the top.
何かの役に立つかもしれないし
Maybe they'll be useful for something.
これは私の周年を記念したグッズということだね
So these are the merch celebrating my anniversary ey.
さてなにがあるんだろう
Let's see. I wonder what they've got.
どれも結構使えそうだから　一緒に見ていこう
They all seem pretty useful, so let's check it out together.
まずは　バケットハット
First up, we got a bucket hat.
イラストは　はまなし先生に描いてもらいました
The illustration was done by Hama Nashi sensei.
コンセプトは私が...みんなの予想通り！ラスボスです！
The concept is me being... you guessed it! The final boss!
リバーシブル仕様でイラストも　すごくかっこいい！
It's reversible and the artwork looks really cool!
たぶん着けると防御力も上がりそうな気がする！
And maybe it would make you feel like it would boost your defense stat!
続いては
And next up,
ランダム属性アクリルキーホルダー！
we got a random attribute acrylic keychain.
ちびキャラは Gurin先生に描いてもらいました
The chibi characters were drawn by Gurin sensei!
どれが出るか楽しみだね！ね！
I wonder which one you'll get ey ey?
そしてアクリルキーホルダーの次は...クッションです！
...And after the Acrylic Keychain, we got a Cushion!
これも Gurin先生に描いてもらいました！
The design for this was also done by Gurin sensei.
両面にイラストが入っていて
The cushion has an illustration on both sides,
サイズ感も使いやすいクッションです
and size wise, it's pretty easy to use as well.
次は～
Next up,
可愛いボロスランプです！
we got this cute Boros Lamp!
明るさを２段階で調整できて
Looks like you can adjust the brightness between two levels,
デザインもすっごく可愛い！
and the design is super duper cute,
暗い場所でも安心だね
you'll be safe even in dark places.
怖い時もボロスがいてくれるよ
When you're scared he's got you.
みんな心配しないで
Don't worry everyone.
そして次は
And coming up next,
シチュエーションボイスパック！
we got a situation voice pack!
タイトルは『悪役クロニーのラストループ』です
The title being Villainous Kronii's Final Loop.
何だか不穏なタイトルだけど
Sounds pretty ominous, but,
聴くのが楽しみ！
I can't wait to check it out.
早くチェックしたいな
I want to check it out
もう聴いちゃう気！
I wanna listen to it already.
そして最後に
And finally,
...if you purchase everything,
you'll also receive a cheki-style card with a foil stamped signature,
along with a bonus voice pack.
The card illustration was drawn by, you guessed it, Hama Nashi sensei.
And as for the bonus voice pack...
it's going to be telling the story of joining hands and heading into the final battle in order to bring the loop to an end.
It's going to be very emotional, so go check it out.
Once more, here is the full line up.
Yeah, every single one of these looks like they'd help me escape this other world, so I definitely want to get them all.
And with that, looks like that's everything.
So, according to Subaru senpai,
all I have to do is sing one more song. So...
whew. Here goes. Let me try it.
営みの
As the hustle and bustle
街が暮れたら 色めき
of the town darkens at night, it lights up.
風たちは運ぶわ
The winds carry away
カラスと人々の群れ
the crows and the crowds of people.
意味なんか
There is no special meaning,
ないさ 暮らしがあるだけ
it's just life going on.
ただ腹を空かせて
Just getting hungry,
君の元へ帰るんだ
I return home to where you are.
物心ついたらふと
As I grew up, I suddenly looked up
見上げて思うことが
and realized something:
この世にいる誰も
Everyone in this world
二人から
came from two people.
胸の中にあるもの
The feeling deep inside your heart,
いつか見えなくなるもの
what will eventually disappear one day,
それは側にいること
it is being right by your side,
いつも思い出して
always remember that.
君の中にあるもの
What you have inside of you,
距離の中にある鼓動
the heartbeat across the distance.
恋をしたの貴方の
I fell in love with your
指の混ざり 頬の香り
intertwined fingers and the scent of your cheek.
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being husband and wife.
みにくいと秘めた想いは色づき
Hidden feelings once thought ugly begin to bloom,
白鳥は運ぶわ
and the swans carry them away,
当たり前を変えながら
changing what is taken for granted.
恋せずにいられないな
I can't help falling in love.
似た顔も虚構にも
With similar faces and even in fiction,
愛が生まれるのは
love is born
一人から
from just one person.
胸の中にあるもの
The feeling deep inside your heart,
いつか見えなくなるもの
what will eventually disappear one day,
それは側にいること
it is being right by your side,
いつも思い出して
always remember that.
君の中にあるもの
What you have inside of you,
距離の中にある鼓動
the heartbeat across the distance.
恋をしたの貴方の
I fell in love with your
指の混ざり 頬の香り
intertwined fingers and the scent of your cheek.
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being husband and wife.
泣き顔も
Your crying face,
黙る夜も
silent nights,
揺れる笑顔も
and your swaying smile,
いつまでも
forever and ever,
forever and ever.
胸の中にあるもの
The feeling deep inside your heart,
いつか見えなくなるもの
what will eventually disappear one day,
それは側にいること
it is being right by your side,
いつも思い出して
always remember that.
君の中にあるもの
What you have inside of you,
距離の中にある鼓動
the heartbeat across the distance.
恋をしたの貴方の
I fell in love with your
指の混ざり 頬の香り
intertwined fingers and the scent of your cheek.
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being husband and wife.
二人を越えてゆけ
Go beyond two people.
一人を越えてゆけ
Go beyond one person.
Where am I?
I'm back!
...or was I asleep?
Was it all a dream?
I dunno.
Oh, my back. Oh, I'm getting old.
That was such a weird experience.
Oh, yeah!
I was going to invite someone over to my place.
And then I was going to ask them to make me something to eat.
Oh, wait. No, I'm still being arrogant.
That's not asking. That's giving an order.
Which, damn right I should.
No, I should be nicer about this.
Make me some food, please. Meow~
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, that's... That's cute.
Yeah, that's more like it. Yeah.
Or not. What are they going to do?
Oh, sorry. Been a long day.
Who am I even talking to?
Anyway...
Yeah. Yeah, I don't know.
Who should I invite?
Is there going to be someone around at this hour?
I gotta think about this...
Oh, what the fu----!!
I Reincarnated as a Villainess?! Ouro Kronii 3rd Anniversary LIVE